<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Yuuxeun</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://yuuxevn.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-07-21T16:03:41.302Z</updated>
  <id>https://yuuxevn.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Yuuxeun</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://yuuxevn.github.io/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://yuuxevn.github.io/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2020-07-20T07:19:18.407Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-21T16:03:41.302Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h6> This is between me, coding and error. </h6>So, from the title it is clear this is like a <i>'trial'</i> program for many developers when using new technology(for some reason hello world I also don't know).<p>I loved computers very much, and when I graduated from junior high school I decided to go to a vocational school and then major in software engineering. so from there I know programming (10th grade school which was about 2 years ago).</p><p>I am also not a person who is very skilled in this field(only 2 years of study), but at least not really a newbie hahaha. the motivation to continue learning is always within me even though I thought of ‘ok, I want to focus on using this language or this framework’, but I realize this is a world of technology which changes very quickly (seriously), if I don’t update with another language/framework maybe I’ll be eroded by age.</p><p>Often I am confused about what part of the focus, whether it’s web, mobile or desktop, not infrequently the feeling of wanting to end it all just because of an error (fuck you). Starting to feel unworthy to be a programmer and always confused with the errors encountered.</p><p>Until now I still feel the same way when an error occurs, it always feels curious that the error hasn’t disappeared. Maybe someone has experienced what I experienced too.</p><p>And of course my feelings will be very happy if the error message changes even though the error is really not fixed. but at least I have been struggling to resolve the error and this is where I usually start using stackoverflow, google and the community is very helpful (most often to the coding school forum hahaha).</p><p>Many developers say that if we have to think of an error as a friend, when we meet him it means we will have new experiences, we will learn new things. The spirit in the face of errors that exist, all can certainly be resolved.<br>remember, it is not only you &amp; erroe that has been experienced by other people too (believe me).</p><p>Okay maybe that’s all this article, thank you for reading.<br><b>Happy coding!</b></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h6&gt; This is between me, coding and error. &lt;/h6&gt;
So, from the title it is clear this is like a &lt;i&gt;&#39;trial&#39;&lt;/i&gt; program for many developers wh
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
