<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Yuxxeun</title>
  
  <subtitle>I have to write the meaning of my life</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://yuxxeun.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-12-01T03:49:58.021Z</updated>
  <id>https://yuxxeun.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Yuxxeun</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>.cult</title>
    <link href="https://yuxxeun.github.io/cult/"/>
    <id>https://yuxxeun.github.io/cult/</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T02:05:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T03:49:58.021Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Bukankah setiap dari “kita” <strong>seharusnya</strong> bisa menulis kode?…</em></p><p>Uji Kompetensi, dari namanya saja sudah menggambarkan kalau kegiatan ini merupakan suatu kegiatan yang bertujuan untuk menilai seberapa <del>ahli</del> kompeten kita dalam bidang yang ditekuni.</p><p>Jauh-jauh hari beberapa guru gue bilang kalau, sekolah akan mengadakan uji kompetensi untuk kelas 12 (dari dulu juga gitu) dan dikabarkan juga hanya ada dua hasil dari ujian tersebut yap, kompeten (mendapatkan sertifikat) dan tidak kompeten (otomatis tidak). Dari situ gue mikir kalau ujian ini besar kecilnya berpengaruh buat gue, karena ya gue pengin kerja di industri ini dan sertifikatnya bisa gue pakai untuk melamar kerja (walaupun tetap butuh portfolio).</p><p>Akhirnya gue mutusin buat belajar lagi tentang materi yang dipakai, buat jaga-jaga aja siapa tau ada yang belum gue pahami. Dan benar saja gue mengalami “sedikit” kesulitan saat mengerjakan soal praktik (karena materi yang dipakai menggunakan bahasa pemrograman C++, yang mana <strong>hanya</strong> dipelajari saat kelas 10).</p><p>Tapi itu bukan menjadi alasan, gue sadar kalau gue “kurang” dalam hal praktik. Maka dari itu gue berlatih terus-menerus.<br><em><code>^seikhlas info, ujiannya teori dan praktik.</code></em></p><p>Singkat cerita hari H dimana ujian tersebut tiba, dan ya gue dan teman-teman mengerjakan soal praktik. Ya walaupun sempat mengalami beberapa <em>error</em> tapi akhirnya gue bisa menyelesaikan programnya.</p><p>Selesai dengan program, gue nyamperin salah satu temen yang berada di ruangan yang sama, dan gue tanya-tanya seputar soal praktik tadi.<br>“Gimana? lancar kan?”, tanya gue (ekspektasi gue dia bisa menyelesaikan juga).<br>Tau jawabannya apa?<br>“Lancar lah, kan tinggal ctrl + v alias <em>copy paste</em>“, semoga lo ga asma dengernya hehe.</p><p>Belum puas? ada juga yang ngasih flashdisk (tau lah isinya apa haha) waktu istirahat.<br>Gue langusng mikir “apa ‘budaya’ kita separah ini?”. Setelah gue sadar, hal tersebut bisa terjadi karena kurangnya pengawasan dari pihak institusi dan kesadaran masing-masing individu. Menurut gue ya mending sadar diri lah (kalau ga bisa ya ngaku aja…HAHA), iya gak sih?</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bukankah setiap dari “kita” &lt;strong&gt;seharusnya&lt;/strong&gt; bisa menulis kode?…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uji Kompetensi, dari namanya saja sudah mengg
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Engineering" scheme="https://yuxxeun.github.io/tags/Engineering/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hopefully..u die soon</title>
    <link href="https://yuxxeun.github.io/Hopefully-u-die-soon/"/>
    <id>https://yuxxeun.github.io/Hopefully-u-die-soon/</id>
    <published>2020-10-30T01:27:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-30T02:03:00.313Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Upss..sorry</em></p><p>Semoga adalah kata untuk sebuah harapan. “Semoga lekas sembuh”, “Semoga sukses”, dsb.</p><p>Buat gue kata semoga ini kesannya lebih pesimis, meskipun kita semua tahu bahwa <em>kita</em> yang merencanakan dan hasilnya tuhan yang menentukan.<br>Jika tidak menambahkan kata “semoga”, kesannya malah seperti sombong. Seakan-akan apa yang diucapkan bakal terjadi.</p><p>“Lekas sembuh ya”, “Sukses ya”.</p><p>Bukankah kita menambahkan kata “semoga” juga karena kita berharap hal tersebut(yang kita semogakan) tercapai, bukan?</p><p>Balik lagi, <strong>kita merencanakan, tuhan menentukan</strong>.</p><p>Entah mengucapkan semoga atau tidak,  gue rasa dua-dua nya sama-sama tahu tentang kalimat sebelum paragraf ini.</p><p>Setelah gue lihat lagi, perbedaanya cuma di eksplisitas. Dengan semoga, kita meng-eksplisitkan suatu pengharapan. Begitu pula sebaliknya, entah menggunakan semoga atau tidak, kita sama-sama berharap.</p><p>Kita sama-sama sadar, bahwasannya kita lemah karena yang maha kuat adalah Tuhan.</p><p>Kita sama-sama sadar, bahwasannya kita hanya bisa merencanakan karena pada akhirnya tuhan-lah yang menentukan.</p><p>Tapi ada satu faktor yang menjadi suatu penentu: <strong>Ikhtiar kita. Usaha kita</strong>.</p><p>Perkataan “Semoga lekas sembuh” ataupun “Sukses ya” tidak akan terwujud bila kita tidak ada usaha untuk sembuh ataupun sukses.</p><p>Karena doa adalah doa, “Semoga tuhan menganpuni dosa-dosaku” kalau terus berbuat dosa, ya lucu, terlihat seperti “Semoga gue gak sakit” tapi menjalani hidup gak sehat. Begitupula dengan kata “Gue gak sakit” ketika menyakini diri sendiri saat menjalani hidup gak sehat.</p><p>Makin kesini gue semakin menghindari kata semoga kepada orang lain sebisa mungkin, gue buat agar seakan-akan dia optimis(yakin/pasti) bisa melakukannya. Terlepas bisa atau tidaknya, itu urusan belakang.</p><p>Yang penting, doa dulu; Usaha dulu, ikhtiar dulu.</p><p>Do it dulu.</p><p>Kemungkinan buruk yang tidak kita harapkan, tidak akan terjadi apabila kita tidak membuat hal itu terjadi. Tapi jangan lupa(apalagi sombong), kita hanyalah manusia. Karena <em>kita</em> adalah milik-Nya.</p><p>Terima kasih, <del>semoga harimu</del> harimu pasti menyenangkan!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upss..sorry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semoga adalah kata untuk sebuah harapan. “Semoga lekas sembuh”, “Semoga sukses”, dsb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buat gue kata se
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Stand Alone</title>
    <link href="https://yuxxeun.github.io/Stand-Alone/"/>
    <id>https://yuxxeun.github.io/Stand-Alone/</id>
    <published>2020-10-13T13:08:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-13T18:17:59.699Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h6>Mastering the Ability to be Alone</h6>Quiet? feels familiar from the first, even like a friend .... really likes that.but why now even become afraid and even hide from it.I don't know, what's wrong with me, maybe the loneliness I feel now is different from the loneliness it used to be.<p>I realize that the current loneliness is more because I want to reach the top of Mount A and not all of my friends / colleagues want to reach the same mountain (I hope, you know what I mean), it’s a sense of loneliness now.</p><p><strong><em><code>Isn&#39;t there one person or several people who have the same goal?</code></em></strong></p><p>of course there is! because actually all friends are in the same camp, but not all of them want to move to get to the top, as if it looks like natural selection, but not explicitly. sounds funny huh? haha, but it’s the choice of each individual, I have no right to sue them. and from there there are fewer and fewer <code>&#39;participants&#39;</code> participating in the event. and yes, this loneliness is getting closer.</p><p>Let’s get over some of the cowardly <strong>sheep</strong> who are comfortable in the camp, ‘cause I have an interesting subject than that.<br>After I saw and heard about Mastering the Ability to be Alone, it was explained that feeling lonely when we want to reach the top of a mountain is natural.<br>and about friends slowly leaving us? of course, they also discussed it.<br>Is it natural? It is reasonable! I repeat it again <strong>N A T U R A L !</strong></p><p>For those of you who are feeling the same way, calm down! you are not alone I also feel that way. It’s quiet, there are no friends to accompany you, but believing it all will pay off, it’s just not easy.<br>Be patient and consistent with what you are pursuing / working on, see you above!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h6&gt;Mastering the Ability to be Alone&lt;/h6&gt;
Quiet? feels familiar from the first, even like a friend .... really likes that.
but why now even
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="lonely" scheme="https://yuxxeun.github.io/tags/lonely/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>6575 days on Earth</title>
    <link href="https://yuxxeun.github.io/6575-days-on-Earth/"/>
    <id>https://yuxxeun.github.io/6575-days-on-Earth/</id>
    <published>2020-09-17T16:33:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-06T05:51:42.297Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h6>Are you still alive? Yes, you!</h6>Long? that's just the beginning, nothing.the journey is just about to begin, brace yourself! the universe isn't that kidding, realize!<p>How good does it feel when the birthday comes, birthday cake? friend? or even a party? it will all come automatically like a machine, aka a celebration and its partner, especially if it’s not a surprise.<br>BUT IT WAS, very long … so long.</p><p>Now? crazy! I just don’t want to do that anymore, it’s nothing, it’s just that when that day comes again and again I feel that there is an increasing burden and I am required to be mature, yes that’s a consequence that must be accepted. Is not it?? or maybe just me? Ah I don’t think so, but I don’t know.</p><p>Every time that day comes I always think <code>&#39;what have I done? (For myself and others)&#39;</code> often confused to answer the question, not to mention other questions (which came from my own head of course).</p><p>But it’s still the very foundation of what comes out of my mind, I will feel like a person having a panic attack when the question of how my future is, not only briefly but I sometimes think about it until I get stressed.<br>it sounds stupid, but that’s how stupid I am.<br>Think things are still far ahead, you idiot!</p><p>now to the point, load.<br>the number of days is increasing, the burden will be heavier and closer, yes how could the pigeon mother find <i><code>food</code></i> for her children, and her child will find <i><code>food</code></i> for her, not to mention if the child is not alone, aka having a smaller sibling, it must be a challenges for children who have smaller siblings. thoughts of ‘can I find <i><code>food</code></i> for my parents and younger siblings?’ it always popped into the child’s head.<br>Wait, what ?? The pigeon is not like that<br>yes, I also know, but that is just a picture, with what I am experiencing at this time. the child’s mind is the same as mine, damn it!</p><p>well, that’s a little what’s on my mind.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h6&gt;Are you still alive? Yes, you!&lt;/h6&gt;
Long? that&#39;s just the beginning, nothing.
the journey is just about to begin, brace yourself! the un
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="fucking-life" scheme="https://yuxxeun.github.io/tags/fucking-life/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://yuxxeun.github.io/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://yuxxeun.github.io/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2020-07-20T07:19:18.407Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-13T17:38:30.204Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h6> This is between Me, Code and Error. </h6>So, from the title it is clear this is like a <i>'trial'</i> program for many developers when using new technology(for some reason hello world I also don't know).<p>I loved computers very much, and when I graduated from junior high school I decided to go to a vocational school and then major in software engineering. so from there I know programming (10th grade school which was about 2 years ago).</p><p>I am also not a person who is very skilled in this field(only 2 years of study), but at least not really a newbie hahaha. the motivation to continue learning is always within me even though I thought of ‘ok, I want to focus on using this language or this framework’, but I realize this is a world of technology which changes very quickly (seriously), if I don’t update with another language/framework maybe I’ll be eroded by age.</p><p>Often I am confused about what part of the focus, whether it’s web, mobile or desktop, not infrequently the feeling of wanting to end it all just because of an error (fuck you). Starting to feel unworthy to be a programmer and always confused with the errors encountered.</p><p>Until now I still feel the same way when an error occurs, it always feels curious that the error hasn’t disappeared. Maybe someone has experienced what I experienced too.</p><p>And of course my feelings will be very happy if the error message changes even though the error is really not fixed. but at least I have been struggling to resolve the error and this is where I usually start using stackoverflow, google and the community is very helpful (most often to the <a href="https://sekolahkoding.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sekolah Koding forum</a> hahaha).</p><p>Many developers say that if we have to think of an error as a friend, when we meet him it means we will have new experiences, we will learn new things. The spirit in the face of errors that exist, all can certainly be resolved.<br>remember, it is not only you &amp; error that has been experienced by other people too (believe me).</p><p>Okay maybe that’s all this article, thank you for reading.<br><b>Happy coding!</b></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h6&gt; This is between Me, Code and Error. &lt;/h6&gt;
So, from the title it is clear this is like a &lt;i&gt;&#39;trial&#39;&lt;/i&gt; program for many developers when
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="hello" scheme="https://yuxxeun.github.io/tags/hello/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
